Welcome back.
Let's discuss about ethylene x.
SC Linux is a labelling system.
Every process has a label.
Every file directory object in the operating system has a label.
Even network ports, devices and potentially hostnames have levels assigned to them.
We write rules to control the access of processed payments to an object label like a file.
We call this a policy.
The kernel enforces these rules.
Sometimes this enforcement is called mandatory access control as part of the Android security model.
Android uses security enhanced Linux to enforce mandatory access control over all processes, even processes
running with root or superuser privileges.
Linux operates on the principle of default denial.
That means anything not explicitly allowed is denied.
It's in the next can operate in two global modes.
One Burmese mode in which permission denials are locked but are not enforced.
Enforcing mode in which permission denials are both locked and enforced.
Android includes a selinux in enforcing mode and a corresponding security policy that works by default
across areas in enforcing mode.
Disallowed actions are prevented and all attempted violations are logged by the kernel to the message
or look at.
So now let's discuss about labels, roles and domains.
NCLEX Linux depends upon labels to match actions and policies.
Labels determine what is allowed sockets, files and processes.
All have labels in easy Linux SC Linux decisions are based on labels assigned to these objects and the
policy defining how they interact.
The policy rules comes in the following form.
For example, allow domain types, classes and permissions where.
A domain is a label for the process or set of process, also called a domain type as it is just a type
for a process.
Type.
A type is a label for the object.
For example, a socket or set of objects a class.
This is a kind of optical assembly file or a socket being accessed.
Now permissions, the permission could be like read or write or one of them in order to make it more
clear.
Let's imagine a system where we define types on objects like cats and dogs.
A cat and dog are processed types.
We have a class of objects that they want to interact, which we call food.
And I want to add types to food that food and as a policy item.
I would say that a dog has permission to eat dog chow food and a cat has permission to eat that child
food.
Initially, next we would write this policy as.
I know that Cat Chow would eat.
Hello, Doc.
Doc Joe would eat.
So here the first keyboard, which is Allo is actually the operation and the dog is actually the high
label type dog domain and dog chow is actually the object and food is actually the class and it is actually
the operation.
So basically we are allowing the dog to eat nocturnal.
With these rules, the colonel would allow the cat process to eat food labelled cattle and a dog to
eat food labelled dog chow.
But in any select system, everything is denied by default.
This means that if the default process tries to eat the catchall, the kernel would prevent it.
So now all we will do some hands on silliness.
And I think after that it would be more for you.